Protecting the Earth from the scum of the universe.
Men in Black is a action, adventure, comedy film directed by Barry Sonnenfeld.
After a police chase with an otherworldly being, a New York City cop is recruited as an agent in a
top-secret organization established to monitor and police alien activity on Earth: the Men in Black.
Agent K and new recruit Agent J find themselves in the middle of a deadly plot by an intergalactic
terrorist who has arrived on Earth to assassinate two ambassadors from opposing galaxies.
Kay, played by Tommy Lee Jones.
Jay, played by Will Smith.
Laurel, played by Linda Fiorentino.
Edgar, played by Vincent D'Onofrio.
Zed, played by Rip Torn.
Jeebs, played by Tony Shalhoub.
Men in Black (abbreviated as MIB) is a 1997 American science fiction action comedy film directed by Barry Sonnenfeld,
based on a script by Ed Solomon, that adapts the Marvel Comics series The Men in Black by Lowell Cunningham.
Tommy Lee Jones and Will Smith respectively star as Agent K and Agent J, who investigate a series of
seemingly unrelated criminal incidents related to the extraterrestrials who live in secret on Earth.
Linda Fiorentino, Vincent D'Onofrio, and Rip Torn
also appear in supporting roles.
Development for the film began in 1992, after producers Walter F.
Parkes and Laurie MacDonald optioned the rights to the comic book series.
Solomon was soon hired to write the screenplay; Sonnenfeld was the preferred directorial choice, which resulted in
delays due to his commitments to other film projects and a failure to secure any alternative directors.
Principal photography began in March 1996 and lasted until that June,
with filming primarily taking place in New York City.
The film's visual effects were helmed by Industrial Light & Magic.
The film's soundtrack contains the theme song of the same name, performed
by Smith, as well as the score, composed by Danny Elfman.
Men in Black premiered at Pacific's Cinerama Dome in Hollywood on June 25, 1997, and was theatrically released
in the United States on July 2 by Sony Pictures Releasing through the Columbia Pictures label.
It received critical acclaim for its screenplay, humour, action sequences,
and the performances and chemistry between Jones and Smith.
The film was a box-office success, grossing more than $589.4 million worldwide and becoming the
third-highest-grossing film of 1997 as well as the ninth-highest-grossing film of the decade.
It won for Best Makeup and was also nominated for Best Art Direction and Best
Original Score at the 70th Academy Awards, among numerous other accolades.
A sequel was released in 2002, a third film was released in 2012, and a
stand-alone sequel was released in 2019, with Jones and Smith absent.
The film explores themes of new york city, cannon,
space marine, flying saucer, undercover.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.